In 1901, this ancient Greek artifact was discovered
1901年  人们发现了一件古希腊的文物
in a shipwreck off the island of Antikythera.
发现于安提基特拉岛的沉船中
3D X-ray scans have revealed
三维 X 光扫描显示
it contains 37 interlocking bronze gears,
它由 37 个相互连接的铜质齿轮组成
allowing it to model the motions of the Sun and Moon
用来建模日月的运动
and predict eclipses decades in advance.
以及推算几十年后的日食
Constructed around 100 or 200 BC,
这架公元前 100 ~ 200 年的
the Antikythera mechanism represents
安提基特拉机械
a sophisticated early computer, the likes of which
代表了复杂的早期计算机
would not be seen again for at least 1,000 years.
在往后的至少一千年里不复存在
Now, of course, this computer didn't work
显然 这台计算机的工作原理
like modern digital computers.
不同于现代的电子计算机
It works by analogy.
它通过模拟来工作
The gears were constructed in such a way that the motions
这些齿轮的构造
of certain dials are analogous
使得拨动这些齿轮
to the motion of the Sun and Moon.
可以模拟日月的运动
It is an analog computer.
它是一台模拟计算机
Here is a simple analog computer
这是一台简单的模拟计算机
for adding two numbers together.
可以求两数之和
If you turn the black wheel some amount
当你把黑色的齿轮转一下
and then turn this white wheel a different amount,
白色的齿轮也转一下
the gray wheel shows the sum of the two rotations.
灰色的齿轮就会显示出两个转动的和
In contrast, this is a digital mechanical computer
而在一台数字计算机上
where you can add two single bit numbers.
则是对两个一位的数加和
So zero plus zero equals zero,
因此 0+0=0
zero plus one equals one, and one plus one equals two.
0+1=1, 1+1=2
These two devices illustrate the differences
这两个设备展现了
between analog and digital computers.
数字计算机和模拟计算机的不同
Analog computers have a continuous range of inputs and outputs,
模拟计算机的输入和输出是连续的
whereas digital only works with discrete values.
而数字计算机只对离散的值进行运算
With analog computers, the quantities of interest
在模拟计算机上
are actually represented by something physical
计算量通过诸如轮子转动了多少
like the amount a wheel has turned,
这些物理量来表达
whereas digital computers work on symbols
而在数字计算机上
like zeros and ones.
则用 0 1 这样的符号来表达
If the answer is, say, two, there is nothing in the computer
如果算出来的结果是 2
that is twice as much as a one.
数字计算机并不会呈现出来 1 的两倍
In analog computers, there is.
而模拟计算机则可以
For thousands of years, people used analog devices
数千年来，人门使用类似
like the Antikythera mechanism or slide rules
安提基特拉机械或是计算尺这些模拟计算设备
alongside digital devices like abacuses.
也使用算盘这些数字计算设备
And up until the 1960s, the most powerful computers
一直到 20 世纪 60 年代
on the planet were actually analog.
世界上最强大的计算机都还是模拟计算机
Digital computers exploded onto the scene
固态晶体管的到来
with the advent of solid state transistors,
使得电子计算机能够大显身手
and now almost everything is digital.
现在几乎所有计算机都是电子计算机
Most people have never even heard of analog computers,
人们几乎没有听过模拟计算机的存在
but today that may all be changing.
但是这一现象可能正在发生改变
Moore's Law, the idea that you can double the number
摩尔定律指出
of transistors on a chip every two years,
晶体管的数目每两年翻一番
it's reaching its limit because transistors
而因为晶体管的体积已经差不多和原子一样小了
are nearly the same size as atoms.
这一定律正在接近极限
Simultaneously, advancements in machine learning
同时，机器学习的发展
are straining the capabilities of digital computers.
对电子计算机的性能提出了更高的要求
The solution to these challenges
而这些困难的解决
may well be a new generation of analog computers.
可能需要依赖新一代的模拟计算机
One of the most important problems humans have faced
预测潮汐这一重大问题
for millennia is predicting the tides.
曾困扰了人们近千年
Napoleon and his men nearly died crossing the Red Sea
拿破仑的军队在穿过红海时
due to a miscalculation of the rising tide,
因为计算涨潮时间的失误近乎丧命
and sailors routinely needed to know the tides
而海员需要知道潮汐
to bring their ships into port without running aground.
以避免船只靠岸时搁浅
Most coastal locations on Earth
地球上许多海岸
experience two high and two low tides per day,
一天涨潮两次退潮两次
but their exact timing varies as does their magnitude,
但是涨潮退潮的时间和程度各不相同
and this is partly caused by local factors
这一部分取决于当地的地理因素
like the depth of the seabed and the shape of the shoreline.
例如海船深度以及海岸线的形状
In the late 1700s, to describe the tidal flow of the oceans
在 18 世纪末，皮埃尔-西蒙·拉普拉斯
Pierre-Simon Laplace derived a set
指出了一套复杂到没有解析解的
of complicated differential equations.
复杂的差分方程
They had no analytical solutions
来描述海洋的潮汐流动
so at the time they were basically useless,
所以在当时来说这近乎没用
but in the process of deriving his equations,
但是在推导式子的时候
Laplace made a key finding.
拉普拉斯有了一个重要发现
Tides are driven at only a few specific astronomical frequencies,
潮汐只取决于少数几个天文频率
including the Moon, the Sun, and the eccentricity of the lunar orbit.
例如日月以及月轨道的离心率
Each one of these factors contributes a sine wave
这些因素各自形成一个正弦波
of a particular amplitude and phase to the total tide curve.
以特定振幅和相位差贡献到潮汐的波形里
If someone could figure out
如果有人能够想出来
how to correctly combine these frequency components,
怎么能正确地组合这几个频率
well, the tides could finally be predicted.
那么潮汐就能够被预测出来
It took nearly a century, but in the 1860s,
William Thomson, later Lord Kelvin, took up the challenge.
Having completed several voyages
to lay the first transatlantic Telegraph cable,
he developed a fascination with the sea
and subsequently he threw his full scientific effort
into measuring and predicting the tides.
Tide gauges at the time used a buoy
to record the height of the sea onto a paper roll.
Kelvin set out to determine how sine waves
with the frequencies identified by Laplace
could add together to produce the observed tidal curve.
The key was to apply the work of French mathematician
Joseph Fourier who had shown how to decompose any function
into a sum of sine waves.
Most English scientists were skeptical of the work,
but Thomson was enthralled by it.
His first paper published at 17 was a defense of Fourier.
While it was straightforward to apply Fourier's analysis
to tidal curves, the computation required was enormous.
First, divide the tide curve up into short time intervals
and for each interval multiply the tide level
by a sine wave with the frequency of interest.
Add up the area of all these rectangles
and divide by the total time
and this gives you a single coefficient,
the amplitude of the sine wave with this frequency.
Then you have to repeat the process
for a cosine function with the same frequency.
Kelvin found that to make accurate predictions,
he actually needed 10 different frequency components
so that is a lot of multiplication and addition
to characterize the tides at just one location.
For each additional location,
you have to perform this analysis all over again.
And this is only half the problem.
Once you have the amplitudes and phases
of the sine functions, you have to add them up
to predict future tides.
Lord Kelvin spent years analyzing
开尔文勋爵投入了数年时间分析和手动预测浪潮
and predicting tides by hand.
Then he had a stroke of inspiration.
他突然有了个大胆的想法
Could you design a machine
你可以设计一种能够自动完成这些计算的机器吗
to carry out these calculations automatically?
In Kelvin's words, to substitute brass for brains.
用凯文的话来说，这是「用黄铜代替人脑」
The resulting analog computers
他造出来的模拟计算机 在随后的近一个世纪内一直在使用
were in use for nearly a century.
They even played a critical role
它们甚至在第二次世界大战中 扮演了至关重要的角色
in the outcome of World War II.
Kelvin started with the problem of prediction.
凯文从预测的问题出发
Adding the sine waves together,
如果你知道它们的振幅和周期，并将这些正弦波加在一起
given you know their amplitudes and phases,
he knew he could create sinusoidal motion
他就能用一个叫做「苏格兰轭」的装置 作出正弦运动的图像
with a device called a Scotch Yoke.
It extracts one dimension from uniform circular motion.
它将圆周运动提取成一维运动
But to make a tide prediction,
但要做潮汐预测的话
he needed a way to combine 10 sine waves together.
他就需要有一种方式能将10个正弦波混合在一起
He needed a mechanical analog for addition.
他需要一个机械来模拟加法运算
Stuck on this problem in 1872, Kelvin boarded a train
1872年 在他被这个问题困住的时候 开尔文登上了一辆火车
for a meeting with the main sponsor of his tidal research,
去和一个他的潮汐研究的主要赞助者，大不列颠协会会面
the British Association.
On the train, Kelvin bumped into a friend,
在火车上，凯文遇见了一位朋友，发明家Beauchamp Tower
inventor Beauchamp Tower to whom he explained his dilemma.
他向这位朋友说明了他现在的窘境
Tower suggested he use Wheatstone's plan
Tower 建议他使用 Wheatstone 的
of a chain passing round a number of pulleys.
将一条链子绕过几个滑轮的方案
And this was exactly the addition mechanism
而这个就是凯文一直在寻找的加法装置
Kelvin was looking for.
By attaching a pulley to each Scotch yoke
通过在每个苏格兰轭上安装一个滑轮
and running a weighted cord around them,
并在他们周围拉上一条加重的绳子
he could mechanically add
他可以机械性地一次增加它们所有的贡献
all of their contributions at once.
He scribbled down the entire plan
他将整个预测机器的方案在他下火车前潦草地画了下来
for this predictor machine by the end of the train ride.
He pitched it to the British Association
他向英国协会提出了这一建议
and secured funding to build it all before he returned home.
并在回家前获得了建造这一切的资金
If you knew the relative contributions
of different frequency components,
如果你知道不同频率成分的相对贡献
Kelvin now had a machine to automate the tedious task
开尔文现在有了一台机器，可以自动完成繁琐的
of predicting future tides.
预测潮汐未来的工作
This was a great leap forward.
这是一个巨大的飞跃
Four hours of cranking the handle
摇动手柄四个小时
yielded a full year of tidal predictions.
就能获得一整年的潮汐预测结果
But for many years, the harder half of the problem
但多年来 这个问题中较难解决
was still done by hand, breaking apart
即把现有的潮汐曲线 分解成其组成频率的工作
an existing tide curve into its component frequencies.
仍然是由手工完成的
To automate this step, Kelvin needed a machine
为了实现这一步骤的自动化，凯文需要一台机器
capable of multiplying the tide curve times a sine wave
能够将潮汐曲线乘以一个正弦波
and then taking its integral.
然后再取其积分
What would such a device even look like?
这样的设备到底是什么样子的呢
With his older brother, James Thomson,
与他的哥哥詹姆斯-汤姆森一起 凯文想出了一个机械积分器
Kelvin came up with a mechanical integrator.
It consists of a ball on a rotating disc.
它由一个旋转盘上的球组成
Due to the rotation of the disc, the further the ball
由于圆盘的旋转
is from the center, the faster it spins.
球离中心越远 它的旋转速度就越快
If the ball is at the very center of the disc.
如果球在圆盘的最中心
It doesn't turn at all.
它根本就不转
And if it's on the left side,
而如果它在左边
it turns in the opposite direction.
它就往相反的方向转动
Now, the motion of the ball is converted into an output
现在 球的运动被转换成一个经由滚轮做出来的输出
via a roller, which moves a pen up or down
而这个滚轮在作为输出的图画纸上 上下地移动着笔
on the output graph paper.
So the way it works is you trace the function
因此 它的工作方式是用测针来追踪你想描绘的函数
you want to integrate with a stylus,
and the stylus controls the position
测针控制球在圆盘上的位置
of the ball on the disc and hence its speed of rotation.
从而控制其旋转的速度
This is transferred through the roller to the output,
这将通过滚轴传递到输出端
which plots the integral of the original function.
绘制出原始函数的积分
Now, to decompose a tide curve,
现在 要分解一条潮汐曲线
we don't just want to integrate the function.
我们不只是想对函数进行积分
We first want to multiply it by a sine wave
我们首先要把它与一个特定频率的正弦波相乘
of a particular frequency, and the way to do this
而做到这一点的方法是
is to make the disc rotate back and forth
让圆盘以该频率来回旋转
at that specific frequency.
Now the rotation of the ball depends not only on where it is
现在 球的旋转不仅取决于它在圆盘上的位置
on the disc, but also on how the disc
而且还取决于圆盘在那一刻是如何转动的
is turning at that instant.
You trace the tide curve with the stylus,
你用测针描画出潮汐曲线
which moves the ball back and forth on the oscillating disc,
它使球在振动盘上来回移动
and the roller sums up the integral
滚筒将潮汐曲线与正弦波的积分相加
of the tide curve times the sine wave.
Simply divide by the total time to get the coefficient.
只要除以总时间就可以得到系数
Several of these ball and disc integrators can be connected
几个这样的球和盘的积分器可以并接起来
in parallel with each disc oscillating
所有圆盘都以不同的频率振荡
at a different frequency to calculate the coefficients
for multiple frequency components at the same time,
来同时计算多个频率成分的系数
Kelvin's analog computers
凯文的模拟计算机
revolutionized our ability to predict tides.
彻底改变了我们预测潮汐的能力
Tidal curves from anywhere in the world could be turned
世界上任何地方的潮汐曲线都可以透过
into a set of sinusoidal coefficients
using the ball and disc harmonic analyzer,
使用球和盘谐波分析器 将由此产生的正弦波加在一起的方式
and the resulting sinusoids could be added together
被转化为一组正弦曲线
to predict future tides
using his Scotch yoke pulley machine.
并使用他的苏格兰轭形滑轮机 预测未来的潮汐
Kelvin's harmonic analyzers were the basis
凯文的谐波分析器 是具有里程碑意义的模拟计算机的基础
for a landmark analog computer
called the differential analyzer,
它被称为「微分分析器」
and his tide predicting machines
而他的潮汐预测机 在19世纪被广泛使用
were used well into the 1960s.
In fact, they were later overhauled
to include 26 frequency components
and used to plan the allied invasion on D-Day.
The Germans expected any invasion to come at high tide
to minimize the time Allied soldiers
would be exposed on the beaches
so they installed millions of obstacles
that would be underwater by mid tide,
many with explosive mines attached,
but the Allies spotted the obstacles and changed tack.
Instead they plan to begin the invasion at low tide.
This would allow demolition teams
to first clear channels through the obstacles.
Then the main forces
could come through those gaps as the water rose.
This would also give landing craft enough time
to depart without getting beached.
The low water times were different
at the five landing beaches by over an hour
so the invasion times were staggered
according to the tide predictions.
- This wasn't the only use
of analog computers in World War II.
Dive bomber aircraft would plummet out of the sky
directly toward their targets at up to an 80 degree angle,
and their rapid descents
made them very difficult to shoot down.
So the US began searching for devices
to automatically aim guns at dive bombers.
Most of the proposed solutions
fell into one of two categories.
Some were analog machines like Lord Kelvin's.
Others were essentially fast calculators.
Mechanical calculating machines like the abacus
had been around for millennia,
but they were far too slow to respond to dive bombers.
These new calculating machines sped things up
by using electrical pulses.
The committee considered naming these devices
after the pulses they used,
but member George Stibitz proposed a more general name,
digital because these machines operated
on numbers themselves or digits.
And this is the origin of the term digital computer,
but digital would have to wait.
Of all the proposals, an innovative analog machine
from David Parkinson went out.
At Bell Labs in New York,
Parkinson had been working on a device
to chart telephone data called an automatic level recorder.
It used a variable resistor called a potentiometer
to control the motion of a pen.
One night after hearing reports
of the harrowing Allied evacuation of Dunkirk,
Parkinson had a dream that he was on the front lines.
I found myself in a gun pit with an anti aircraft gun crew.
A gun there was firing occasionally,
and the impressive thing was
that every shot brought down an airplane.
After three or four shots one of the men in the crew
smiled at me and beckoned me to come closer to the gun.
When I drew near,
he pointed to the exposed end of the left trunnion.
Mounted there was the control potentiometer
of my level recorder.
When he woke up, Parkinson realized the device
he was building to control a pen
could be scaled up to control an anti-aircraft gun.
- He shared this idea with his supervisor
and after receiving approval from the military,
they set out to make Parkinson's dream a reality.
Researchers at Bell Labs had recently invented
an analog electrical device
called an operational amplifier or op-amp.
It could perform mathematical operations with voltages,
like addition and multiplication.
They used these op-amps to create an analog computer
that could solve the ballistics equations
for anti-aircraft guns.
Using radar and optical sights to obtain the speed, altitude
and direction of enemy planes,
the M9 Gun Director, as the computer was called,
could rapidly calculate
the correct trajectory and fuse setting.
Potentiometers were used
to ascertain the direction the gun was pointing.
This was not the first electric analog computer,
but it was an important one.
In World War I, it took an average of 17,000 rounds
to take down a single airplane.
In 1943, after the invention of the M9,
it took an average of only 90.
During the war, the US invested big in analog computers.
战争期间 美国在模拟计算机上下了血本
If you break down their total military budget,
如果把他们的军事支出分开来看
the third largest single expense was
单项支出第三大的是
the development and production of an incredibly complex
诺顿轰炸机瞄准器的开发和生产
mechanical analog computer called The Norden Bombsight.
一种复杂得不可思议的机械模拟计算机
Unfortunately, they didn't get their money's worth.
不幸的是 他们这笔钱花得不值
Designed by the eccentric Dutch engineer Carl Norden,
这台瞄准器出自离经叛道的荷兰工程师卡尔 诺顿之手
the Norden Bombsight was built
用于高精度空中轰炸
to enable high-precision airborne bombing.
It implemented 64 different simultaneous algorithms,
它实现了 64 种不同的模拟算法
including one that compensated
包括一种方法
for the rotation of the Earth as the bomb fell.
用于补偿投弹时地球的转动
The Norden was one
诺顿瞄准具是战争期间
of the most closely guarded secrets of the war.
受到严格保护的绝密之一
To prevent the technology from falling into enemy hands,
为了防止它落入敌手
American bombardiers carried handguns
美国轰炸员配备了专门的手枪
specifically to destroy it in the event of a crash.
用于在坠机时破环它
But despite its hype and funding,
尽管它来头不小且耗资甚巨
the Norden didn't work as advertised.
诺顿瞄准具的表现不如人意
With over 2,000 fine parts,
它由 2000 个以上精细部件组成
it required extreme precision to manufacture.
需要极高的精准度来操作
The problem with analog computers
模拟计算机的问题在于
is that the physical device is a model for the real world.
它本身是一个描述真实世界的模型
So any inaccuracy in the components
所以源自任何部件的不精确性
translates into inaccuracy of the computation.
都会转换成计算的误差
And since there will always be some slop
同时  由于部件的连接存在偏差
in the connections between parts,
if you run the same calculation twice,
如果运行相同的计算两次
you won't get the exact same answer.
结果不会完全相同
In the American campaign against Japan,
在美国进攻日本的战役中
bomber crews using the Bombsight were unable
轰炸员无法使用这种瞄准具
to destroy critical Japanese war infrastructure,
破坏日本的关键军用设施
and ultimately the US abandoned
最终美国弃用了
its precision bombing approach
这种精准轰炸的途径
and instead blanketed whole Japanese cities in napalm.
转而使用凝固汽油弹对日本城市进行地毯式轰炸
As the war progressed, digital computers gained traction.
随着战争的推进，数字计算机获得了大家的关注
The digital and electronic Colossus machines
在英国布莱切利园中巨大的数字电子机器
of Bletchley Park in the UK
were critical to breaking German codes.
在破解德军密信中发挥了巨大作用
In the United States, the military invested
在美国 军方投资了一个极其复杂且昂贵的数字机器
in an enormously complex
and expensive digital machine known as ENIAC.
名叫ENIAC（电子数值积分计算机）
It was designed to speed up the calculation
它被设计用于加速陆地炮弹射表的计算
of land artillery firing tables.
At the time, these were computed
在当时 这些计算是用积分分析器
using differential analyzers,
the analog mechanical computers
那个基于开尔文的和弦分析器制成的
based on Kelvin's harmonic analyzer.
模拟机械式计算机完成计算的
Although not finished until after the war,
虽然这个电子计算机直到战争完成后也没有完成
ENIAC demonstrated the power of digital computers.
ENIAC展现了电子计算机的力量
It's considered by many to be the first modern computer.
它被大多数人认为是第一台现代定义的电脑
What really opened the door to this digital revolution
真正打开电子革命大门的 是克劳德·香农
was the discovery made by Claude Shannon
in his 1936 Master's thesis.
在1936年其在研究生时的发现
He showed that any numerical operation can be carried out
他发现任何的数字运算可以透过
using the basic building blocks of Boolean algebra.
基础的构建布尔运算区块来执行
Two values, true or false, also notated as one or zero,
真或假这两个数值 也可以记为0或1
and three operations, and, or, and not.
以及与、并及否 三种运算
This makes digital computers
这让数字计算机成为了理想的万能计算机器
the ideal versatile computing machines.
In contrast, each analog computer
与之对比的是 每一个模拟计算机
is an analog for only one type of problem.
只能是对一种问题的模拟计算
Furthermore, since digital computers
更重要的是 因为数字计算机能以0和1进行运算
operate on ones and zeros,
they're more resilient in the face of noise.
它们在面对噪音（计算）的时候能具有更好的适应性
It would take a large error to mistake a one for a zero
or vice versa, whereas even small errors in analog computers
can grow and ultimately swamp the signal.
So these days, everything is digital.
Our phones, computers, and internet data centers,
even TV and radio is now being broadcast as digital.
And the advantages are obvious.
Since digital devices operate on symbols,
usually zeros and ones, they provide exact answers
and repeat the calculation and you get the same result.
They are robust to noise.
Plus since only a few components
are required to perform virtually any computation,
those components have been miniaturized and optimized,
making digital computers
the ideal universal computing machines.
So you would think analog computers would be long gone,
a relic of the distant past,
but analog may now be making a comeback.
There are startups actively working on analog computers.
Why is this happening? What could be the benefit of analog?
I wanted to put all of this into one video,
but the story is too good to bury 20 minutes in
so that is coming up in part two.
Be sure you're subscribed to the channel
to be notified when that comes out.